Guide to the Samuel Clarke Bushnell Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Samuel Clarke Bushnell Papers
1877-1928
RG 77
Yale University Divinity School Library
10
(21 boxes)
The papers consist primarily of manuscript sermons dating from 1877 to 1928. Samuel Clarke Bushnell (1852-1928), a Yale Divinity School graduate, was a Congregational minister in Massachusetts and Connecticut.
Bushnell, Samuel Clarke, 1852-1930
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
1852 Mar 8 Born in New Haven, CT
1874 B.A., Yale College
1877 B.D., Yale Divinity School
1879 Ordained as Congregational minister
1878-1890 Served First Congregational Church in New Bedford, MA
1890-1920 Served Orthodox Church (Pleasant Street Congregational) in Arlington, MA
1917-1918 Alumni Lecturer, Yale Divinity School
1920-1928 Resided in New Haven; preached at United Church; acting pastor there 1922-1923
1928 Died
Scope and Contents
The collection consists almost entirely of manuscript sermons, arranged chronologically.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1923
II. Sermons and Addresses, 1877-1928
III. Other Writings, 1921-1922, n.d.
Congregational churches -- Connecticut; Congregational churches -- Massachusetts; Clergy; Bushnell, Samuel Clarke, 1852-1930; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Correspondence, 1923; Series I
  - Letter from SCB to Mr. Welch, 1923 Jan 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Sermons and Addresses, 1877-1928; Series II
  - Sermons and addresses, 1877-1880 (Box 1)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1881-1884 (Box 2)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1885-1888 (Box 3)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1889-1894 (Box 4)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1895-1896 (Box 5)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1897-1898 (Box 6)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1899-1900 (Box 7)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1901-1902 (Box 8)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1903-1904 (Box 9)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1905-1906 (Box 10)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1907-1908 (Box 11)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1909-1910 (Box 12)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1911-1912 (Box 13)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1913-1914 (Box 14)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1915-1916 (Box 15)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1917-1918 (Box 16)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1919-1921 (Box 17)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1922-1923 (Box 18)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1924-1928 (Box 19)
  - Sermons and addresses, 1928 (Box 20)
  - Sermons and addresses (Box 21)
- Other Writings, 1921-1922, n.d.; Series III
  - Prayers written by SCB, 1921-1922, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)